Skills

User Research, User testing, User flows, Branding, Wireframes & Prototypes, App design, Marketing, Copyediting, Project management

Tools

Adobe XD, Figma,
Balsamiq, Photoshop,
Excel, Word/Pages,
Keynote, Youtube, basic
html, Social Media

Education

01-02/2022 Frontend Design Course Career Foundry, Berlin

04-12/2021
UX Design Immersion
Career Foundry, Berlin

2002-2004
MBA Certification in
Economics, Marketing,
Organisational behaviour,
Human resource
management
Edinburgh Business School

1999 BA (Hons) Modern Languages Manchester Metropolitan University

Languages

English - Native German - Fluent French - Fluent Italian - Basic Spanish - Basic

THOMAS MANSFIELD - UX DESIGNER

PROFILE

From Paris to London and Berlin via Manchester and onwards into Switzerland, I have been fortunate to collect knowhow and experience both personally and professionally from a great spectrum of people and environments.

London and Paris planted the seeds for my love of gastronomy, travel and languages. Manchester toughened my resolve, fulfilled my thirst for great music and laid down an academic foundation for an all-round creative/business career. Berlin opened new doors both creatively and academically and provided a gateway to design thinking, business acquisition, creative freedoms and ultimately to tackling and fulfilling the user experience. Switzerland provides the backdrop for my next adventure.

CAREER

UX Design student, Berlin/Biel — 2021-Present

Completing online UX Design (Immersion) and Specialism (Frontend Design) courses Design journey of a mobile responsive App from conception to high-fidelity wireframes and prototype. Frontend design of portfolio web site (HTML, CSS, JS).

Chef de Cuisine, Gärbi Restaurant, Biel — 2016-Present

Day-to-day responsibility of kitchen. Catering and events.

Design and production of marketing materials. Food and menu design.

English teacher, Rudolf-Steiner School, Biel — 04/2017-07/2022

Design, preparation and teaching of learning materials for 1st, 5th and 6th years.

Independent Translator, Biel/Berlin — 2001-Present

Technical, educational and cultural text translation (German-English). Copywriting and text editing (project work and one-off jobs)

Layout and formatting.

Chef de Cuisine, Betahaus Café, Berlin — 2010-2015

Day-to-day responsibility of kitchen, food, menus, hygiene, etc.. Catering/event acquisition, organisation and implementation.

Design, construction and management of new lunch/apero/catering kitchen. Food and menu design and layout.

Proposals & Contracts Manager / BusOps, Parexel, Berlin — 2007-2009

Project acquisition, management and implementation in the field of clinical trials. Excel/Keynote/Stakeholder meetings.

Freelance / Travel — 2005-2007

Writing a novel, translation, copy-editing, diving, world travel.

Project Manager, MVV Consulting, Berlin — 2000-2004

Preparation of proposals and contracts for EU-financed reconstruction projects, subsequent management and international liaison with stakeholders.

Project Manager, GAD Marketing, Berlin — 2000-2005

Web, flyers, brochures, legal copywriter for IT clients (full-time and freelance)